几百万年前
Several Million years ago
南极洲：现代
Antartica : Present day
韦尔博士
Dr. Weir
彼得
Peter.
看见了没？没效果
You see? Nothing.
卡尔森，回来
Carson, get back here.
我是可以坐那个椅子上整整一天的，
但是什么也不会发生
I could sit in that chair all bloody day
long and nothing’ll happen.
- 纯粹浪费时间
- 劳驾，韦尔博士
- It’s a waste of time.
-Excuse me, Dr. Weir.
他连试都没试
He’s not even trying.
这种科技只对特殊的基因有反应，
这基因可是是他发现的
He’s the one who discovered the gene
this technology responds to.
没错啊，不过他说他要是没发现就好了
Yeah, well,
he said he wish he never had it.
真的吗？
Really?
我知道难以置信，你能相信吗？
I know, can you believe that?
我们什么时候都可以对你
进行第三次测试的，罗德尼
We could always test you a third time, Rodney.
哼，这还真好笑呢
That’s very funny.
我们总共只找到几个人...
We have only found a handful of people
身上具有符合这种古代科技要求的基因
who are genetically compatible with
the Ancient technology,
除了你自告奋勇想要与它产生互动外
and despite your heroic effortsto interface
ours with theirs…
我们还需要其他每个人
都来坐这椅子试试，包括贝克特博士
…we need every one of them to sit in this chair
including Dr. Beckett.
可我该怎么做？他怕这玩意儿
What am I supposed to do?
He’s afraid of the thing.
这台椅子控制着人类已知的最强武器
This chair controls the most powerful
weapons known to humankind,
我也怕这玩意儿
I’m afraid of the thing…
不过每次有人坐在它上面时
But every time someone sits in it
我们就对建造了这前哨基地的古人
多了解了一点
we learn something new about
the Ancients who built this outpost.
贝克特博士应该为他的基因优秀而自豪
Dr. Beckett should be proud
he’s genetically advanced…
谈不上优秀，这只是随机特性而已
Not more advanced.
It is a random characteristic.
你好像对此很不以为然啊
我是说这套基因的说法
This really bothers you,
this whole gene thing.
哦，看来我是被嫉妒冲昏头脑罗
Oh, clearly I am overcome with envy.
啊，正好碰见我要找的人了
Ah, just the people I need to see.
跟我来
Come with me.
本来失踪城市的位置正一点点被我们定位
We’ve gotten closer, and closer,
to finding the location of the lost city
但是最后看来好像我们彻底找错地方了
but it turns out we’ve been looking
in the wrong place all along.
我们本来以为我们找到一个星门的地址
Now, we thought we had a stargate address.
六个符号代表了空间坐标
Six symbols representing coordinates in space
由此可以得知古人离开南极洲后，
前往的星球所在位置
that determine the location of the planet
the Ancients went to after they left Antarctica.
但是，最近，我们发现了第七个符号
Now, recently, we determined a seventh symbol.
表示出发地，地球？
The point of origin, Earth.
不是的
That’s not it.
那你的地址就一定是错误的
Then your address must be incorrect.
不是错误，而是不完整
Not incorrect, incomplete.
你什么意思，杰克森博士？
What are you saying, Dr. Jackson?
这是个八个符号的地址
It’s an 8 symbol address.
我们在寻找的可能超出了我们的想像
What we’re looking for may be further
away than we ever imagined,
但是还不算偏的离谱
but its not out of reach.
亚特兰蒂斯？
Atlantis.
就是亚特兰蒂斯，我想我们可以去那了
Atlantis. I think we can go there.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
Episode 1 & 2 Rising
by Team24 & SG-66
Forom.com & seriestele.net
阿帕奇，黑鹰，眼镜蛇，鱼鹰
（都是直升机型号）
Apache, Black Hawk, Cobra, Osprey.
为了南极洲你可是做了不少训练啊
That’s a lot of training for the Antarctic.
这可是我没有去过的大陆啊
It was the one continent I never set foot on.
这是我最不喜欢的大陆之一
It’s one of my least favorite continents.
我有点喜欢这里
I kinda like it here.
你喜欢这里？
You like it here?
是的，长官，十分钟后抵达
Yes sir.
Be there in about 10 minutes sir.
听我说，我们都玩过这套把戏了
我不是你要的人
Look, we’ve been through this.
I’m not your man.
别停
Keep moving.
我是博士，医学博士
I’m a doctor. A medical doctor.
没什么好怕的
There’s nothing to be afraid of –
你不明白，我会毁掉这玩意儿的
You don’t understand, I break things like this –
这东西都过了几百万年还丝毫无损，
它也一定能过你这关的
This device has survived for millions of years intact
-it will survive you-
现在，坐下，闭上眼睛，集中精神
Now sit down, close your eyes and concentrate.
还是一样，没效果
Again, nothing.
这次，试试在脑中建立一幅图像，
想像我们在太阳系中的位置
This time just try to imagine an
image of where we are in the solar system.
我觉得我感觉到什么东西了
I think I feel something.
可能和午饭有关
It could be lunch related.
闭嘴，集中精神
Shut up, and concentrate --
我做了什么？
What did I do?!
快把我们送回下面去！
Get us back down there!
所有靠近的飞机请注意，我们发现一枚
可以自行搜索目标的飞行器
All inbound aircraft, we have a rouge drone
that can seek a target on it’s own.
立即着陆，关闭引擎
我重复一遍，这不是演习
Land immediately and shut down your engines,
this is not a drill! I repeat…
太晚了，小心
It’s too late. Hang on.
右急转
Break right.
我说的是右
I said right.
我听到了，长官
I’m getting to that, Sir.
我告诉你了，我不是你要的人
I told you I was the wrong person –
现在这不重要了，赶快做点什么
It doesn’t matter now, just do something.
比如呢？
Like what?
卡尔森，在那武器还没伤人之前，
赶快集中精神，让它停下来
Carson, concentrate on shutting that
weapon down before it hurts someone.
我看不见那东西
I can’t see it.
拉起！拉起！
Pull up, pull up!
现在怎么样？
What about now?
现在这样就很好
Now’s good.
关掉它
Shut it down.
长官，那鬼东西到底是什么？
Sir, what the hell was that?
等等看
Wait for it –
快出去！
Get out!
我想我办到了
I think I did it.
那是不一样的
That was different.
对我来说差不多
For me, not so much.
谢帕德少校报告说，
那飞行器似乎已经停止运转了
Major Sheppard is reporting the drone
appears to have been incapacitated.
奥尼尔将军的直升机丝毫无损
并且重新起飞了
General O’Neill’s helicopter is unharmed
and on it’s way again –
还有七分钟
Seven minutes out.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
天啊
Holy Crap.
杰克！
Jack!
丹尼尔！
Daniel
热烈欢迎
Warm welcome.
不是我的错，你是怎么...？
Wasn’t me. How’d you manage to, uh –?
怎么逃过一劫，
没在半空中被打个稀巴烂的？
Keep my ass from getting blown out of the sky?
那都得归功于约翰·谢帕德少校
的出色飞行，他喜欢这里
The exceptional flying of Major John Sheppard.
He likes it here.
出色？你喜欢这里？
Exceptional – You like it here?
我们少废话，直入主题如何？
What say we cut to the part
where you start talking real fast?
啊，韦尔在这里
Ah, Weir’s in here.
嘿！什么也别碰
Hey! Don’t touch anything.
遵命，长官
Yes sir.
我们查出大概500万到1000万年前
古人把他们带着他们整个城市去了某处
I figure the Ancients packed up their entire city and left
somewhere between five and ten million years ago.
你是说他们的城市会飞
In their… flying city?
是的
Yes.
怎么了？
What?
会飞的城市？
Flying city?
呃，要知道他们可是
建造了星际之门的种族
Well, uh, keep in mind this is the race
that built the stargates
他们最喜欢兴师动众
–They did everything big.
那，他们为什么要离开？
So, why’d they leave?
为什么离开？呃，这谁知道呢？
Why’d they leave?
Um… Who knows?
我们知道在地球上，
古人们陷入了一场瘟疫
We know the Ancients on Earth were
suffering from a plague.
也许他们中间有人希望重头来过，
在一个新星系里面繁衍下去
Maybe some of them were trying to start over-
seeding life in a new galaxy.
可能古人们就是那么想的，
但关键是我们知道他们去哪里了
Maybe that’s what Ancients do…
The point is we know where they went.
飞马座
Pegasus.
是的，那是本星系群中
的一个矮星系的名字
Yes, it’s the name of a dwarf galaxy in a local group.
经过这么长时间了，
我们还有希望见到他们吗？
After all the time is there any hope
of actually meeting them?
这谁知道？
不过这原因还不够我们去一趟的吗？
Who knows?
But isn’t that reason enough to go?
我已经花了几个月
为这次探险挑选队员了，博士
Well I’ve been choosing members
for this expedition for months, Dr.
需要被说服的不是我
I’m not the one who needs convincing.
哦，我已经被说服了，祝你们开心
Oh I’m convinced.
Have fun.
呃，事情不是那么简单
Uh, it’s a little more complicated than that.
我们需要Zed-P-M来给星门补充能量
We need the Zed-P-M to power the gate.
什么？
What?
就是Z.P.M.，他是，呃，加拿大人
The Z.P.M. He’s, uh, he’s Canadian.
对不起，我没懂
I’m sorry.
哦，就是零点模块，将军
Oh, the Zero Point Module, General.
你在烈火焚烧之星发现的古代能源
The ancien power source you recovered
from Praclarush Taonas,
而现在那正给前哨基地提供防御能源
and that’s now powering the outposts’ defenses.
从那以后，我断定它产生的巨大能量...
I have since determined that it generates
it’s enormous power
来自于一个独立的次空间时间区
产生的真空能量
from vacuum energy derived from
a self-contained region of subspace time.
解释的不错，可惜没用
That was a waste of a perfectly good explanation.
我的回答是不行
The answer’s no.
他们真幸运，我不知道那东西从哪来
我就是集中了精神
…They’re lucky, I don’t know where it came from.
I just had to concentrate and
然后那飞行器就自己停止了
the drone shut itself down.
这么说是你干的
So you were the one.
我？
Me?
是你发射那东西打我的
You’re the one who fired that thing at me.
听我说，我们在作研究
这科技比我们先进不知多少光年
Look, we’re doing research, working with
technology that’s light years beyond us,
然后我们犯了个错误
我非常非常的抱歉
and we make mistakes.
I’m incredibly, incredibly sorry.
好啦，下次小心点好吗？
Well next time just be a little more careful, okay?
我刚才就是这么说的
That’s what I said-
那东西到底是什么啊？
What the hell was that thing anyway?
你说那飞行器？那是古人们造出来
保卫这个前哨基地的武器
You mean the drone? The weapon
the Ancients built to defend this outpost.
谁？
The who?
你有进入这里的安全许可对吧？
You do have security clearance to be here?
是的，是的，奥尼尔将军
刚刚把那东西给我
Yeah, yeah, General O’Neill just gave it to me.
而你居然不知道星际之门？
Then you don’t even know about the stargate.
什么？
The what?
杰克，你知道打开通向
另一个星系的星门要消耗大量能源
Jack, you know that gating to another galaxy
requires an enormous amount of power.
是的，我知道，换条路走
Yes, I do. Find another way.
没有其他的路了
There’s no other way.
你觉得亚特兰蒂斯上面会有
更多这种Z什么东西吗？
You think there are more of these Zed-things in Atlantis?
是的，而且谁知道我们还能找到什么呢
Yes, and who knows what else we could find.
我们谈论的可不仅仅是另外一个文明，
是星门的建造者
This isn’t just some other civilization we’re
talking about, these are the gate builders.
潜在的知识和科技财富...
The potential wealth of knowledge and technology,
比自从我们进入星门以来
遇见的任何东西都要重要
it outweighs anything we’ve come across
since we stepped through the stargate.
但是，鉴于进行这次旅行所需的能量
数量之大，很可能你们无法返回
Well, with the amount of power you’ll need
to make this trek, odds are it’ll be one way.
是的我们知道
Yes we know
但是对于人类的利益
将远大于风险，将军
But the benefit to humanity is
far greater than the risk, General.
而且我的探险队员中，
每个人都愿意承担这一风险
And it is a risk that every one of
my expedition members is willing to take.
他们认为基因在这里被用作
某种类似密码的东西，
They think the gene was used as a sort
of genetic key if you will, so that only
以保证只有他们的种族才能操控
这一危险而又强大的科技制品
their kind could operate certain
dangerous or powerful technologies.
就是说有些人和古人有相同的基因了
So some people have the same
genes as these Ancients.
这种特别的基因非常罕见，
不过总体来说他们和我们很相像
The specific gene is very rare, but on
the whole they look very much like we do.
事实上，他们是第一批进化成这种
类型的，而我们是第二批
In fact, they were first.
We’re the second evolution of this form.
古人们早在数百万年前就探索了整个银河
The Ancients having explored
this galaxy for millions of years before
少校，请不要
-Major, please don’t-
别这样，我和那些家伙
有相同基因的概率能有多少？
Come on, what are the odds of me having
the same gene as these guys?
事实上，微乎其微
Quite slim, actually.
韦尔博士！你别动！
Dr. Weir!
Don’t move!
这位是谁？
Who is this?
我说过不要碰任何东西
I said don’t touch anything.
我只是坐下而已啊
I just sat down.
少校，想像一下我们在太阳系所处的位置
Major, think about where we are in the solar system.
这是我办到的？
Did I do that?
我们会出发去探寻一个全新的古代文明
We could be on our way to discovering
an entirely new Ancient civilization.
最好的情况下，我们会碰见真正的古人
而且他们还愿意帮助我们
Best case scenario, we meet actual
Ancients who are willing to help us.
但是如果不是这样，将军，我们需要他
But if we don’t, General we need him.
对不起，博士，我需要丹尼尔留在这里
Sorry, Doc. I need Daniel here.
我说的是谢帕德少校
I’m talking about Major Sheppard.
哦，你不是已经有了一堆人
都可以使用这个古代科技制品了吗？
Oh, don’t you have a dozen or so people already
who can use the Ancient technology?
是的，如果集中精神，受过训练
他们能让它工作
Yeah, with concentration and training
they can make it work.
而约翰·谢帕德，他似乎天生就能做到
But John Sheppard, he does it naturally.
你知道，我查过他的记录
You know, I’ve checked into his record-
我知道他在阿富汗执行任务时
所谓污点的始末
I know about the whole supposed
black mark in Afghanistan,
他那是为了救三个军人的性命
he was trying to save
the lives of three servicemen.
那可是在执行任务时
拒绝服从直接的命令
Disobeying a direct order in the process.
我也读过您的档案，将军，求你了
I have read your own file, General. Please.
这样啊
Right.
好吧，这是你组织的探险
你要是想要他的话，就直接问他吧
Okay, it’s your expedition.
You want him, you ask him.
我问过了
That’s the thing, I have.
真的？
Really?
回程的路不长，所以我长话短说
This isn’t a long trip so
I’ll be as succinct as possible.
呃，这的确够短的
Well, that’s pretty succinct.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我告诉韦尔博士了，
我说我会考虑
I told Dr. Weir, you know,
that I’d think about it.
然后？所以？那么？到底怎样？
And? So? Well? What?
不是有意冒犯，长官，
但是我们才被一个外星导弹攻击完
With all due respect, Sir,
we were just attacked by an alien missile.
然后我就发现我自己有特殊的变种基因
Then I found out I have some mutant gene.
然后就冒出来这个星门，
还有什么去其他星系的探险
Then there’s this stargate thing and
these expeditions to other galaxies.
你知道吗，这不仅仅是你的事情，
谢帕德，不仅如此
You know, this isn’t about you Sheppard.
It’s a lot bigger than that.
现在，此时此刻，参不参加
这个行动似乎就是我的事
Right now, at this very second, whether I decide
to go on this mission or not seems to be about me
那我问你个问题
Let me ask you something.
你干嘛要做个飞行员？
Why’d you become a pilot?
我认为不想飞的人都是疯子
I think people that don’t wanna fly are crazy.
而我认为不想通过星门的人
也一样是失败者
And I think people who don’t wanna go thru
the stargate are equally as whacked.
如果等我们抵达迈克墨多克的时候，
你还是不能答应的话，我都不想要你了
Now if you can’t give me a ‘yes’ by the time
we reach McMurdoch, I don’t even want you.
西蒙，如果你在看这段录像
Simon, if you’re watching this,
这意味着总统心地善良，
给予你安全许可了
it means that the President has been kind
enough to grant you security clearance.
我不是去另外一个国家，执行外交任务
I’m not going on a diplomatic mission
to another country.
我是通过一个叫做星门的仪器，
去另外一个星系的另外一个星球
I’m going to another planet, in another galaxy,
by means of a device called a stargate.
数百万年前，曾经有一种生物，
我们称其为古人
Millions of years ago there was a race
of beings we call the Ancients…
他们用这种星门在我们的银河系内
建立了一套网络
…They created a network of these stargate
throughout our galaxy,
以便他们可以自由穿行于各个星球之间
in order to travel freely among their worlds…
我们不知道原因，但是大概500万到
1000万年前，他们离开，去了另外一个星系
…We don’t know why, but the left for another galaxy
somewhere between 5 and 10 million years ago…
走的时候，他们带走了他们整个城市
那座城市就叫做亚特兰蒂斯
…taking their entire city along with them.
That city was called Atlantis.
我一直在组建一支探险队
I have been assembling an expedition team…
试图找到亚特兰蒂斯，并且期望能
找到那很久以前就离开的古人们
…in order to try to find Atlantis, and hopefully
the Ancients that left Earth all those years ago…
我想要做这个，西蒙，全心全意的想
I wanna do this, Simon, with all my heart.
你对我很了解，你知道
我是不可能放弃这种机会的
You know me well enough to know
I could never turn down an opportunity like this,
但是我希望有机会告诉你...
but I wanted the chance to tell you…
“您拨打的用户现在不在服务区内”
"the cell of the customer you're trying to reach
is curently outside the covered area"
好吧
Ok.
我是说我已经把可能性缩小到
三个东西上了，但是过了一个星期，我...
I mean I narrowed it down to about
3 things, but after a week, I ...
我没有...有谁会说这些人说的语言吗？
I don't under ... Does anyone else here speak
the language these guy's are speaking?
我只需要几分钟完成我的工作
而你站在这里毫无帮助
I just need a couple of minutes to finish my work,
and you're not helping by standing there.
如果你5分钟内还不能让它动起来
我就不要了
You’ve got 5 minutes to get it going
or I’m leaving it.
这里的每件设备都被双重甚至三重检查
过了，起飞准备已经做好，别再查了
Everything in here has been double checked and
triple checked and cleared for takeoff, leave it alone.
听我说，上校，我不对你负责
Look, Colonel, I don’t answer to you.
他对我说了同样的话，长官
He said the same to me, Sir.
那你的手枪是干什么的？
That’s what your sidearm is for.
你看，每个符号代表的地址都
告诉我们的星门...
You see, each chevron address is
what tells our gate
在我们星系外面寻找的一个点
因此直到他定位之前，我们都不知道在哪
to look for a point in space outside our galaxy,
so we won’t know until it locks.
我们做好准备了？
We there yet?
我们只差迈凯博士了
We’re just waiting on Dr. McKay.
现在应该可以工作了
It should work now.
好的，中士，试试看
Okay Sgt., give it a try.
当ZPM察觉到它连接上星门以后，
它就会变亮
The Zed-P-M should light up when
it senses a conductive connection to the gate.
请大家注意听我说好吗？
Can I have everyone’s attention please?
好啦，我们准备好了
All right, here we go.
我们准备尝试进行连接
We are about to try to make a connection.
我们无法预计这将消耗多少能量
We have been unable to predict exactly
how much power this is going to take
而我们可能只有一次机会
and we may only get the one chance at this.
所以如果我们可以建立一个稳定的虫洞
我们就不会冒险关闭星门
So if we are able to achieve a stable wormhole,
we’re not gonna risk shutting the gate down.
我们会派移动式机器人分析探测器过去
查看是否适合人类生存，然后就出发
We’ll send in the MALP robot probe,
check for viability, and go
所有的一切就只有一次机会
Everything in one shot.
你们每个人都是自愿参加这个任务的，
而你们代表了数十个国家
Now every one of you volunteered for this mission,
and you represent over a dozen countries.
你们是世界上最优秀和最聪明的人
You are the world’s best and brightest,
而就我们即将进行的探险来看，
and in light of the adventure we are
about to embark on,
你们也是最勇敢的
You are also the bravest.
我希望有天我们都能回来，而且发现了
一个有待人类探索的全新领域
I hope we all return one day having discovered
a whole new realm for humanity to explore,
但是如我们所知的，
我们可能永远无法回家了
but as all of know,
we may never be able to return home.
因此我给你们一个最后机会
放弃参与这项行动
I’d like to offer you all one last chance
to withdrawal your participation.
开始拨号程序
Begin the dialing sequence.
我把话说清楚，少校
你来此不是出于我的选择
Let me make myself clear, Major.
You are not here by my choice.
我肯定当你了解我以后，
你会喜欢我的，长官
I’m sure you’ll warm up to me once
you get to know me, Sir.
只要你能记住是谁在发号施令
As long as you remember who’s giving the orders.
是韦尔博士，对吧？
That would be Dr. Weir, right?
第三符号编码完成
Chevron three encoded.
第四符号编码完成
Chevron four encoded.
很好
Nice.
谢谢
Thank you.
第五符号编码完成
Chevron five encoded.
第六符号编码完成
Chevron six encoded.
马上就要开始了
This is it.
说真的，博士，放松点，你让我很尴尬
Seriously, Dr., Calm down.
You’re embarrassing me.
我一生中从来没这么兴奋
I’ve never been so excited in my entire life.
第八符号锁定完成
Chevron eight is locked.
派出移动式无人分析探测器
Send the MALP.
我们收到探测器传回的信息了
We have MALP telemetry.
我们面对的是什么？
What is it we’re looking at?
转入零点锁定
Switching to zero locks.
雷达显示空间很大
The radar indicates a large room?
结构很完整
It’s structurally in tact?
大气分析仪显示那里有氧气
The climactic sensors say there’s oxygen,
没有明显的有毒物质
no measurable toxins;
适合人类生存
we have viable life support.
看来我们不需要放弃了
Looks like we’re not getting out of this.
韦尔博士，你可以出发了
Dr. Weir, you have a go.
谢谢你，长官
Thank you, Sir.
出发了，我们不知道还剩下多少能量
Let’s go people,
we don’t know how much power we’ve got.
警卫队1队，2队先出发
Security teams 1 and 2, you’re up first.
其余人等待我们的信号再跟上来
All other personnel will follow on our signal.
一旦到了那一面，就继续前进
Once on the other side, keep moving,
确保出发区域的安全，跟我来！
clear the debarkation area. On my lead…
等等，上校
Hold on, Colonel.
我们一起过去
We go through together.
够公平
Fair enough.
-杰克，我现在出发不算太晚......
- Jack, it’s not too late for me to-
- No.
我现在还来得及......
- I could just grab my-
- No.
一切正常
All clear, it looks good.
探险队，出发!
Expedition Team, move out.
穿过时感觉如何？
What does it feel like?
痛彻心肺，先生，哦嚯！
Hurts like hell, sir.
警卫队1队和警卫队2队检查当前区域
Teams one and two secure the immediate area.
其它人在有新命令之前
检查开放区域
Everyone else find an open space and park it until instructed otherwise.
那是谁弄亮的？
Who’s doing that?
警卫队，发现外星人了吗？
Security teams, any alien contact?
- 没有，长官
- 警卫四队这里没有，上校
Negative, Sir.
Team four negative, Colonel
灯会自己启动
The lights are coming on by themselves.
人到齐了
That’s everyone.
奥尼尔将军
General O’Neill,
-我从飞马星系亚特兰蒂斯基地发出的问候
Atlantis Base offers greetings from the Pegasus Galaxy.
-你可以切断星门的能量了
You may cut power to the gate.
这看起来像艘船 宇宙飞船
They look like ships. Spaceships!
我喜欢它
I love it.
韦尔博士，你一定要过来看看
Dr. Weir, you have to see this.
-我有很多东西要看，你们小心点
I have a lot of things to see.
Just be careful.
我什么都没碰
- I didn’t touch anything.
- Relax, Major.
放松点，少校，好像整个建筑感觉到
我们的到来，从冬眠中苏醒了一样
It’s like the entire complex is sensing
our presence and coming to life.
这里曾经是控制室
This has got to be the control room.
这很明显是他们的拨号回家装置
This is obviously their version of a DHD
哦，非常明显
Oh, obviously.
这可能是能量控制系统，可能是电脑接口
This area could be power control systems,
possibly a computer interface.
- 嗨嗨，你干嘛不搞清楚呢？
- 好的
- Hey, hey. Why don’t you find out.
- Right.
韦尔博士，我是萨姆勒上校，
你能下来到我这看看吗
Dr. Weir, Colonel Sumner.
Can you come down and meet me please?
我们在地下三层
We’re three levels down, come in.
马上过去
Right away.
我们只能搜索一部分，这地方太大了
We’ve only been able to secure a fraction
of the place, it’s huge.
这可能真的是消失的古城亚特兰蒂斯？
So it might really be the lost city of Atlantis?
我认为这个猜测不错
I’d say that’s a good bet.
哦，上帝！
Oh my god.
我们在水底下
We’re underwater.
我们在几百英尺的海洋下面
I’d say we’re under several hundred
feet of ocean.
如果我们无法拨号回去，这可能是个麻烦
If we can’t dial out,
this could be a problem.
上校，韦尔博士 我们在水底下
- Colonel, Dr. Weir.
- We’re underwater.
是的，我正想告诉你
Yes, I was just, uh, coming to tell you.
很幸运有一个力场挡住了 ...水…
Fortunately there’s some sort of force
shield holding back the water-
这太奇特了，不是吗？
Oh that is impressive, isn’t it?
贝克特博士发现了一样东西，
你该过来看看
Uh Dr. Beckett has found something
you should, uh, see.
希望能在飞马座繁殖新的生命
…In the hope of spreading new life in a galaxy
飞马座上原来是没有生物的
where there appeared to be none.
很快，新的生命开始生长和繁荣 这儿......
Soon, the new life grew and prospered, here…
- 这是全息图，录像会反复播放
- 我们在这里也建立了一套星际之门
- It’s a hologram, the recording loops;
- Here, as before, we built a system of Stargates,
我已经看了第二遍了
- this is my second time through.
-  so that fledgling civilizations
- 我们漏看了多少？
- 不多
- What have we missed?
- Not much.
- could travel between the stars,
交换知识和友谊
exchanging knowledge and friendship.
很快，上千个星球都结出了这种文明的果实
In time, a thousand worlds bore
the fruit of life in this form.
有一天我们踏入了暗黑世界，
那里沉睡着可怕的敌人
Then one day our people step foot on a dark
world where a terrible enemy slept.
我们从未遇到过比我们强大的生物
Never before had we encountered beings
with powers that rivaled our own.
我们太自负，因此没有好好准备 敌人以多袭少...
In our overconfidence we weren’t
prepared, and outnumbered.
...对没有防备的人类世界大开杀戒
The enemy fed upon the defenseless
human worlds like a great scourge,
最终只剩下亚特兰蒂斯城
until finally only Atlantis remained.
这个城市强大的防卫
足以抵挡他们的可怕武器
This city’s great shield was powerful enough
to withstand their terrible weapons,
但我们被攻击了很多年
but here we were besieged for many years.
为了拯救最后的幸存者
In an effort to save the last of our kind
这个伟大的城市被我们沉到了海底
we submerged our great city into the ocean.
亚特兰蒂斯星门是唯一
连接地球和飞马星系的通道
The Atlantis stargate was the one and only
link back to Earth from this galaxy,
最后的幸存者通过它回到我们曾经的家园
and those who remained used it to return
to that world that was once home.
在那里亚特兰蒂斯的幸存者们
过着他们的生活
There, the last survivors of Atlantis lived
out the remainder of their lives.
这个城市沉睡在海底
This city was left to slumber
期待有一天我们能够回来
in the hope that our kind would one day return.
亚特兰蒂斯的传说是真的
Huh. So the story of Atlantis is true.
被沉到海底的伟大城市
A great city that sank in the ocean.
只是没有发生在地球上
It just didn’t happen on earth.
也许古希腊人是从幸存的古人那里听到这个故事的
Well the ancient Greeks must have heard
it from one of the surviving Ancients.
我不喜欢听到他们饱受欺凌
I don’t like the fact that they
got their asses kicked.
让我们从头再看一遍
Let’s see it again from the beginning.
停下！关掉！
Stop! Turn it off.
整个城市的能量水平直线下降
Power levels throughout the city
are dropping like a stone.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
如果不立刻停止所有的活动 我们就死定了
That if we don’t stop everything we’re
doing right now, we are dead.
告诉我这不是我的错
Please tell me this is not my fault.
不是 谢谢
- No.
- Thank you.
就我们现在所知的来看，
这个城市由3个零点模块提供能量
From what we’ve been able to ascertain the city
is powered by three Zero Point Modules.
2个已经耗尽了，还有一个
也快到了最大熵值了
Two are entirely depleted and
the third is reaching maximum entropy.
如果到了就用不了了，到时候将无法挽救
When it does, it’ll die too
and nothing can reverse that.
告诉我最坏的情况
Just tell me the bottom line.
抵挡海水的力场已经弱到了
能承受的最小水平了
The force field holding back the ocean has collapsed to its minimum sustainable levels.
但是看看，这儿，还有这
See here, and here,
力场已经抵挡不住，城市就进水了
where the shield has already failed
and the city is flooded.
可能是几年前发生的 这个部分可能因为星门的保护而没有被破坏
It could have happened years ago, this section is
probably more protected because of the stargate.
如果它彻底被破坏了怎么办？
What if it fails completely?
不用说如果，这只是时间早晚问题
It’s a matter of when, not if.
萨姆勒上校，你必须立刻命令
警卫队停止搜索这个城市
Colonel Sumner, to stop searching the city immediately.
you need to order your security team
所有警卫队员退回到大厅集合
All security teams fall back to the gate room.
情况不妙
It’s not gonna be good enough.
我们还有多少时间？
All right, well how much time do we have?
这很难说，几个小时，如果我们
减少能量消耗也许能维持几天
It’s hard to say. Hours, maybe days
if we minimize power expenditure.
我们自己的发动机呢？
What about our own power generators?
我们正在发动
We’re working on that, but with our most
即使我们用我们最先进的发动机 也会很快就会不够用
advanced naquada power generators,
the equations are coming up far short.
所以我们需要去寻找更多的ZPM
So we need to find more ZPMs.
如果不能搜索这个城市，我们怎么能找到呢？
Well how do we do that
if we can’t search the city?
如果有更多的ZPM，我们能够检测到
If there were more here,
we’d be able to detect them.
我们能使用星际之门吗？
Can we use the stargate?
附近没有地方有足够的能量
去开一个虫洞返回地球
There’s nowhere near enough power
to open a wormhole back to earth.
也许去这个星系的某些地方可以
Maybe somewhere in this galaxy.
那会相对容易点
That’s relatively easy.
幸运的是，一些古代科技
还用那种老式按键系统
Fortunately, some Ancient technology still
uses good ‘ole fashion push buttons,
所以我们能够进入星门控制系统
so we’ve been able to access
the stargate control system
并且进入图书馆，得到数据库中
一系列已知的星门地址
and a library of known gate addresses
in the database.
这并不是全部 看看这个
That’s not all, look at this.
很像地球星门上的拱形
Just like the Iris on the earth gate.
还在用能量，还在用能量，还在用能量
Using power, using power, using power.
至少我们不需要与敌人战斗
At least we don’t have to deal
with any uninvited guests.
上校，召集一个警卫队
Colonel, assemble a team.
我们需要安全港，最好是另一个能量源
We need safe harbor, or better still,
another power source.
福特中尉，警卫队1队和2队
立刻集合，各就各位
Lt. Ford, gather security teams one
and two; everyone gear up.
我希望你也去
Major, I’d like you to go along.
好的，女士
Yes ma’am.
现在，选择地点 开始拨号吧
All right, pick an address; start dialing.
第一编码完成
Chevron one encoded.
罗德尼
Rodney.
好的
Fine
机动分析研究室探测器准备前往侦察
Ready MALP 4 for off-world recon.
探测器显示可以存活
The MALP reads full viability
星际之门附近也没有动静
and no immediate signs of activity
around the stargate,
但会是漆黑一片
but its pitch black.
现在我们要使用身份鉴别系统
对任何靠近星门的人进行鉴识
For now, we’re going to use the tried and true system
of identification for inbound gate travelers.
我们出发吧！
Let’s move out.
求求你们，不要伤害我们！
Please, don't hurt us!
请不要，他们只是在玩耍！
Please, they’re just playing.
这没事吧，谢帕德？
Everything okay here, Sheppard?
没事，长官 只是几个孩子
Yes, Sir, just a couple of kids.
郝林
Halling.
我不知道那是什么意思
I don’t know what that means.
那是他的名字
It’s his name.
郝林，很高兴认识你
Oh, Halling.
It’s nice to meet you.
你们是来这做生意的吗？
Are you here to trade?
做生意？ 是的，我们是商人
Trade, yes. We’re… traders.
我告诉你多少次了，
晚上不要在森林里玩耍
Now how many times have I told you
not to play in the forest after dark?
真高兴你没出什么事
I’m just glad you’re safe.
泰勒希望见见你
Teyla will wish to meet with you.
过来吧
Come.
帕克，史密提，你们负责守卫星门
Parker, Smitty, you’re on gate duty.
通知亚特兰蒂斯基地，通知韦尔博士
Dial Atlantis base and let the good doctor know
我们正在和当地的居民进行接触
we’ve made contact with the indigenous people.
长官，你不介意我问你件事吧
Sir, if you don’t mind my asking,
我注意到你和谢帕德少校之间有矛盾
I’ve noticed you’ve got
a problem with Major Sheppard.
中尉，这主要与他的记录有关
My problem, Lieutenant, is with his record.
我不喜欢不服从上级命令的人
I don’t like anybody who doesn’t
follow the proper chain of command.
是的，长官
Yes, Sir.
那个戴的面具有什么用?
What was that mask you had on?
帮你在黑暗中看清东西，试试看
Helps you see in the dark, check it out.
喔呜，让我看看
Whoa. Let me see.
哇，能给我吗？
Whoa. Can I have it.
不行
No.
你这是什么面具？
What’s the mask you got on?
这个？
This?
幻影族
The Wraith.
幻影族是什么人？
The Wraith. What’s that?
你不知道吗？ 你来自什么世界?
You don’t know? What world do you come from?
我能去那儿吗？
Can we go there?
恐怕不行
Afraid not,
我们从很远很远的星球来的
I come from a galaxy far,
far away.
我是郝林
It’s Halling,
我带来了几个来自远方的人
I bring men from away.
进来吧
Enter.
他们想来做生意
These men wish to trade.
呃，很高兴认识你
It’s, uh, nice to meet you.
我是泰勒·伊玛根，特岗的女儿
I am Teyla Emmagan, daughter of Tegan.
马歇尔·萨姆勒上校
Colonel Marshall Sumner,
谢帕德少校
Major Sheppard,
福特中尉
Lieutenant Ford.
我们没有什么特别需要
We have very few specific needs.
我们不和陌生人做生意
- We do not trade with strangers.
是吗？
- Is that a fact?
我们只是想互相认识一下
Well then, we’ll just uh, we’ll have to get to know each other.
我，我喜欢法拉利赛车，大学橄榄球赛，
任何时速超过200英里的东西我都喜欢
Me, um, I like, uh, Farris Wheels, college football, anything that
goes more than 200 miles per hour.
先生，这些话对他们没什么意义
Sir, that’s not gonna mean anything to them.
我只是随便说点什么打破僵局
Feel free to speak up,
I’m just trying to break the ice.
这些人帮不了我们，
最好不要跟他们浪费时间
These people can’t help us,
I’d rather not waste the time.
每天拂晓前，我们的族人都要喝一种粗茶
Each morning, before dawn,
为了迎接即将到来的一天
our people drink a stout tea to brace
us for the coming day.
你们和我们一起去吗？
Will you join us?
我很喜欢喝茶
I love a good cup of tea.
现在你对我的了解又更进了一步
Now there’s another thing you know about me.
我们可以说是朋友了
We’re practically friends already.
直到太阳升起，我们发现那个
We didn’t even know
it was there until the sun came up.
看起来他们要准备的东西还不少
Looks more promising than
anything else these folks have to offer.
很多防御所，很漂亮的小山谷 选址，选址，选址
Plenty of shelter, nice little valley…
location, location, location.
他们住的这个地方并不安全
The city of the Ancestors is not safe.
我们自己能解决
- We can handle ourselves.
幻影族就要来了
- The Wraith will come.
这些幻影族是什么人？
Who are these Wraith?
我们从来没碰到过不知道幻影族的人
We have never met anyone who did not know.
现在你终于碰到了
Well you have now.
如果幻影族没有入侵你们的家园，
你们应该回到那里
If the Wraith have never touched
your world you should go back there.
我们也想，但回不去
Oh we’d like to, but we can’t.
女士，看现在的情况是，我们遇到了点麻烦
See, here’s the thing, Ma’am,
我们需要一个安全的地方呆一会
we’ve got ourselves into a bit of a bind. We may need a safe place to stay for a while.
我们族人一直坚信如果我们回到自己
原来的城市，幻影族就会来攻击我们
Our people have long believed that the Wraith will come
if we venture into the old city.
但这个想法我们一直没有证实
But, it is a belief
we have not tested in some time.
先生们
Gentlemen.
听着，我不在意他们说什么，
但这个城市值得看看
Look, I don’t care what they say,
that city’s worth a look.
更不用说这儿可能会有ZPM，
只是他们不知道或者不在乎
Not to mention the possibility there could be ZPMs there that they don’t know or care about.
幻影族如果是全息图上
那个女人提到的敌人怎么办？
What if the Wraith are the enemy
the Ancient hologram lady is talking about?
这些都表明我们应该离开亚特兰蒂斯，
去另一个能防御的地方
All the more reason for us to have a defensible
position should we need to abandon Atlantis.
呆在这，尽可能的找到更多信息
Stay here and find out what you can.
福特，你回到星门，把情况汇报给韦尔
Ford, you head back to the gate
and report in to Weir.
告诉她我们几小时后就会有结果
Tell her we’ll have answers for her in a few hours.
遵命，长官
Yes, Sir.
呃，我猜这只有你和我？还有他
Well, guess it’s just you and me … and him.
你们的头看着我，好像当我不存在一样
Your leader looks through me as if I were not there.
我呢？
Do I?
没有
- No.
你们真的回不了你的星球了？
You truly cannot return to your world?
真的
- No
那有些东西你需要看一下
Then there is something you should see.
那地方有多远？
How much further is this place?
不远
Not far.
罗德尼，告诉我一些好消息 没有
Tell me some good news, Rodney.
I can’t do that.
这个防御设备已经将海水
阻挡了好几个世纪了
The shield has held back the ocean for centuries.
也许它还能撑几年
And probably would have kept going for
years more,
但我们的到来改变了这一切
but our arrival changed that.
现在城市和海洋之间只剩下一薄层了
Now it’s nothing more but a thin
shell between the buildings and the water.
我们已经停止了搜索
- We stopped exploring-
但已经对它造成破坏
- The damage is already done.
大约1小时前这个城市
稍远点的那块已经被淹没了
Another section of the city on the far side
was flooded an hour or so ago.
即使我们光呆在这里，能量也在消逝
Even occupying this room is draining power.
只要萨姆勒上校报告说那边安全，
我们必须立即撤离
We need to evacuate the moment
Colonel Sumner reports back it’s safe.
你是说我们必须放弃这个城市？
You’re saying we have to abandon the city.
我们离开得越早，防御层才会撑得越久
The sooner we leave,
the longer that shield holds.
我小时候常在这玩
I used to play here as a child.
我觉得幻影族最后一次大袭击的时候 我们的幸存者就躲在这里
I believe this is where the survivors
hid from the Wraith during the last Great Attack.
让我来点
Let me get it.
我们很久以前就学会了使用火
We mastered fire long ago.
我猜是这样
Guess so.
这是什么？
What’s this?
几年前被我弄丢了
I lost this years ago.
你怎么...？
How did you-
它就在那儿放着
It was just lying right over there.
反射出光芒
It was reflecting off the light.
有人画了很多壁画？
Someone’s been busy, huh?
这个洞里的壁画非常多
The drawings in the caves are extensive.
一些壁画有上千年甚至更长的历史
Many must date back thousands of years, or more.
这个代表了你们城市的毁灭？
Does this represent the destruction of your city?
这幅壁画远远早于那个时候
This drawing far predates that.
难道有人能预知会发生什么事？
So, what?
Someone knew it was gonna happen?
我相信这已经发生过很多很多次
I believe it happens again, and again.
幻影族等我们繁衍到一定的数量
The Wraith allow our kind to grow in numbers.
当这个数到达到某个点
And when that number reaches a certain point
他们就会回来抓他们的人类奴隶
they return to cull their human herd.
有时候他们来需要几百年时间
Sometimes a few hundred years
will pass before they awaken again.
我们去过很多星球
We’ve visited many, many worlds.
但是没有哪个星球没被幻影族染指
I know of none untouched by the Wraith.
最后一次屠杀是在五个世代之前
The last great Holocaust was five generations ago.
他们还是回来了
Still they return,
这次人数更少以显示他们强大的力量
in smaller numbers,
to remind us of their power.
这是一种地狱般的生活
That’s a hell of a way to live.
我们不停的转移营帐
We move our hunting camps around.
我们尽力让孩子们不要生活在恐惧里
We try to teach our children
not to live in fear,
但这很难
but it is hard.
我们中的一些人能感觉到幻影族的袭击
Some of us can sense the Wraith coming.
那给了我们预警
That gives us warning.
我们该走了
We should go,
天快要黑了
it will be dark soon.
嗨，这白天很短
Man, days are short here.
谢帕德少校，我是萨姆勒上校，回话
Major Sheppard, this is Colonel Sumner. Come in.
上校，我是福特中尉，
谢帕德少校现在联系不上
Colonel Sheppard, this is Lt. Ford. Major Sheppard’s
out of radio range at the moment.
他到底在哪？
Where the hell is he?
我想泰勒想带他看些什么东西
I think Teyla wanted him to see something.
注意防卫
Defensive positions!
上校，星门附近有动静
Colonel, we have gate activity here.
上校，三架敌机朝你的方向飞过去了
Colonel, three bandits headed your way.
隐蔽！
Take cover!
怎么了？
- What is it?
幻影族
- The Wraith.
别管了，津透！
Just live it!
Jinto!
朝目标开火！
Fire at that target!
泰勒！
Teyla!
上校，他们在地面上包围了我们
Colonel they’re on the ground,
they’re all around us!
泰勒！
Teyla?
他们并不在那儿
They are not really there.
别相信你看到的，那是幻影族制造的假象
Do not trust your eyes. The Wraith
can make you see things that are not there.
我们必须快点
We must hurry.
上校，我是谢帕德，
你们看到的地面上的东西只是幻影
Colonel, this is Sheppard. What you see on the ground is just an illusion.
集中火力朝飞船开火
Concentrate and fire on the ships.
朝飞船开火！朝飞船开火！
Fire at the ships!
贝慈，朝它射击！ 它们到处都是，长官
- Bates, snap out of it.
- They’re everywhere, Sir.
把它射下来！
Take that thing down.
泰勒，泰勒！
Teyla. Teyla!
长官，上校被抓走了
Sir, the Colonel. They’ve taken him.
星门再次打开 两架敌机正在靠近它
The gate’s coming on again.
Two enemy ships approaching.
让它飞走吧
Let ‘em go,
上面有我们的人
there are friendlies on board.
注意拨号装置，牢记编码！
Look at the dialing device;
burn those symbols into your mind.
×娘养的！
Son of a…
救命，救救我
Help! Help me!
我找不到我父亲了
I can’t find my father.
它在这
Here it comes.
我该看哪儿？
What am I looking for?
你看那儿，又有一部分防御层不起作用了
There… another part of the force field just failed.
我想我们时间不多了
I don’t think we have much time.
我们该怎么办？
How are we doing?
如果我能多一天时间
Look, if we can just buy ourselves another day,
也许我们可以.....
maybe we can-
这个城市牺牲了自己的部分区域，
为了保持主要部位的完整
The city is sacrificing parts of itself in order to maintain
但灾难性的损坏是不可避免的
these main areas, but catastrophic failure is inevitable.
我从来没有想到我能找到失踪的古人城市
亚特兰蒂斯完好无损
Not in my wildest dreams did I hope so completely untouched, so pristine…
to find the lost city of the Ancients
而我们除了离开没有别的方法？
and we have no choice but to walk away from this?
这是为了拯救它
- In order to save it.
为了谁去拯救它？
- To save it for whom?
我们没有足够的能量去发送信息
We don’t have enough power to send a message.
地球上的人会认为我们迷失了
As far as earth is concerned, we’re just
going to be missing; presumed lost.
我们会回去的，只要我们
在飞马星系上找到能源
We’ll be back. We’ll find
a power source somewhere in Pegasus.
我们还没有萨姆勒上校的消息，
不知道他那情况如何
We have yet to hear from Colonel Sumner,
we have no idea what’s out there.
不能再等了，我们必须离开，现在！
We can’t wait. It is time to go, now.
大家请注意，我是韦尔
Attention all personnel, this is Weir.
准备立即撤退
Stand by for immediate evacuation.
开始拨号
Dial the gate.
有一个虫洞进入这里
We’ve got an incoming wormhole.
我读到了福特中尉的身份验证码 让他进来
- I’m reading Lt. Ford’s identification code.
- Let him in.
进来吧，同志们，离拱门远点
Step in folks, move away from the puddle.
谢帕德少校
Major Sheppard!
谢帕德少校，这些人是谁？
Major Sheppard, who are all these people?
当地的幸存者，我们被袭击了
Survivors from the settlement;
we were attacked.
萨姆勒和我们的一些人被抓走了 发生什么事了？
Sumner and some of our men were taken.
What’s going on?
我们没有精力去管别人的事了
We are in no position to help anyone right now.
这到底怎么了？
What the hell’s going on here?
我们准备离开这里
We were about to abandon the city.
回去是一个很烂的主意 夏普勒少校,防御层抵挡不住了，海水会冲进来淹没我们
Major Sheppard the shield is about to fail and
the ocean is about to come crashing in on us.
你有更好的地方去吗？
Do you have a better place for us to go?
津透，我们可以通过星门去其它地方吗？
Jinto, you have any other address
where we can gate to?
有，很多
Yes, many.
他只是个孩子
He’s just a boy.
我是津透 她会很高兴认识你的
- I am Jinto.
- She’s pleased to meet you.
防御层崩溃了
The shield is collapsing!
我正在拨号
I’m dialing an address.
不，等等 她是正确的
- No wait!
- She’s right.
我们在移动
We’re moving!
我们好像在水面上
We’re on the surface.
我本来只希望见到明天
I was hoping for another day.
但看起来好像我们得到的不仅仅如此而已
It looks like we just got a whole lot more than that.
我们不要浪费这一机遇
Let’s not waste it.
伙伴们，听着
People listen up.
先不要休息，直到他们把两台设备搬离甲板 我们现在出发
No one gets to sit down until they carry two pieces of equipment
off this deck. Now let’s go.
最后一个零点模块已经耗尽了
The last Zero Point Module is depleted,
虽然我们发动机的能量不能阻挡海水，
但有限的能量已经恢复了
but limited power has returned now that our
generators aren’t trying to hold back an ocean.
生命支持系统还在运行，
这个星球的空气可以呼吸
Life Support systems are working,
but the planet’s atmosphere is breathable,
不会引起过敏
not withstanding the inevitable allergens.
现在我们最先进的发动机
可以为防御层提供足够的能量吗？
So now could our naquada generators supply
enough power to the shield for defensive purposes?
远远不够 我们在海面上，又没有防御层，就是个靶子
- Not even close.
- On the surface without a shield; we’re target practice.
上校我已经完全意识到这一点，不过谢谢你的提醒
I’m acutely aware of that Major,
but thank you for reinforcing it.
你什么时候能告诉我幻影族
把萨姆勒上校和其他人抓哪去了？
When can you tell me where the Wraith
took Colonel Sumner and the others?
即使有了福特中尉提供的6个编码，
还是会有数百种组合
Even with the six symbols Lt. Ford provided, - there are still hundreds of permutations-
720个？
- 720.
是的，我当然知道。
Yes. I knew that of course…
我只是奇怪你怎么也会知道？
I’m just… surprised you do.
把无法锁定位置的坐标除去
Take away the coordinates you can’t get a lock on,
当你找到坐标，就发送一个机动分析探测器
and that’s you’re one.
And when you find it, send a MALP.
少校，过来一下
Major, a word.
让我来猜猜 你不愿意让我去拯救他们
Let me guess,
you’re not gonna let me rescue my people.
少校，你连他们是死是活都不知道
Major, you don’t even know if they’re alive.
但不管怎样不能让他们在敌人手上
You don’t leave people in the hands of the enemy.
而我们这次谈话这么避人耳目
And the fact that we are having this conversation in private
让我明白你知道这是不对的
lets me know that you know damn well that it’s wrong,
而且会大大有损你的领导力
and it will totally undermine your leadership.
所以作为一个有头衔的军官，我...
So as ranking military officer I-
好吧，先闭嘴！听我说一会，好吗？
All right, just shut up
and listen to me for a moment, all right?
喂，我们对幻影族了解有多少？
Come on, what do we know about the Wraith.
我们仅仅知道他们是摧毁古人的敌人
One of the few things that we do know is that they are the enemy that defeated the Ancients.
当我们刚开始使用在地球上发现的星门后
When we first began to use the stargate we found on earth
我们就有了大麻烦，为什么？
we got ourselves into serious trouble. Why?
我不需要回答你的问题
- I don’t need to answer your question-
- Because the people in charge
因为指挥者在行动时不考虑后果
didn’t consider the ramifications before they reacted.
他们带走了我们的人，你让我怎么行动？
They took our people.
How am I supposed to react?
我们无力抵抗，你也这么说
And we’re defenseless,
you said so yourself.
你有没有想过进行这种愚蠢的营救...
How do you know going off
on some half-assed rescue mission
可能会把他们引到我们家门口？
isn’t going to bring them
all right back here to our doorstep?
也许真的会 但这么做是正确的 为什么？因为就是这样
Maybe it will, but it’s the right thing to do.
Why? Because it is.
约翰 如果我们不这么做，我是说现在
- John-
- If we’re not gonna do this, and I mean right now,
我们就掉头，准备回去吧 因为他们要来了
let’s just turn tail and pack up.
Because they’re coming-
你怎么知道？
You don’t know that.
我们的人在敌人的手上
Our people are in the hands of the enemy, Doctor.
你知道这意味着什么吗？
Do you know what that means?
幻影族发现我们的基地只是时间问题
It’s just a matter of time before the Wraith
figure out that this is the base of our operations.
我只是需要更多的信息
I just need more information.
我是说谁会知道呢？ 也许我们可以协商出一个和平......
I mean who knows?
Maybe we could negotiate a peaceful-
和平解决？ 你开玩笑吧？
Peaceful? Are you kidding
在他们出现之前几个小时我们才到那
We weren’t there for more than
a few hours before they showed up.
他们会来有没有可能是因为你？
Is it possible they came because of you?
你把这些人带回来，可能会泄漏机密
And that one of these people you brought
back here with you tipped them off?
很有可能 所以你的这个决定没有经过深思
- It’s possible.
- See that is exactly the kind of snap decision I am referring to.
他们并不是坏人
They’re not all bad people.
你知道如果我们想呆在这儿，就需要朋友
And you know, if we’re
gonna stick around here we need friends.
好吧，我明白你的意思了
Okay, I see your point.
现在你也要明白我的立场
Now you see mine.
如果完全没有成功的希望，
我不会批准一次营救行动
I will not authorize a rescue mission unless I am sure there is at least a remote chance of success.
我不想让更多优秀的人去送死，包括你
I’m not sending more good people,
including you, to their deaths.
好的
Okay.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我们在哪？
Where are we?
你知道将会发生什么事吗？
Any idea what to expect?
不知道
No.
你的朋友说过，如果我们走进废墟，
幻影族就回来
Your friend was the one who said the Wraith would come if we went down into the ruins.
也许你应该留意他的警告
Perhaps you should have heeded his warning.
我怎么知道他说的对不对？
How do I know he’s not the one who told them?
有人来了
Someone comes.
我是马歇尔·萨姆勒上校
I’m Colonel Marshall Sumner-
不，留下他
No. Please.
把我带走吧
- Take me in his place.
别，还是带我吧
- No, take me.
我们就是你要找的人，对吗？
We’re the ones you’re after, right?
我是他们的头
I’m their leader.
他们没有必要向你解释
They have no need to explain themselves.
是的，我明白了
Yeah, I got that.
我们正在接受可视遥测数据
We’re receiving visual telemetry.
我什么也没有看到
We can’t see anything.
没有大气分析数据
No atmospheric readings at all.
等一下，那是什么？
Wait, what was that?
转动摄像机
Rotate the camera.
哦，机动分析探测器已经发射了
Well… there goes that MALP.
在太空里
It’s in space.
这是在一个飞马星系另一侧的
一颗星球的高轨道上
It’s in high orbit around a planet
on the far side of the galaxy.
你肯定定位没错？
You’re sure this is the right address?
这是我们唯一能锁定的目标
It’s the only one we could get a lock on.
好吧
Very well.
关掉它
Shut it down.
对不起
I’m sorry.
跟我来，少校
Come with me, Major.
觉得你能驾驶它吗？
Think you can fly it?
我们来试试看，怎么样？
What do you say we find out?
贝克特博士，你想给我看什么？
Dr. Beckett,
what was it you wanted me to see?
这些细胞里没有正常的人类抑制蛋白质
These cells have none of the normal
human inhibiting proteins whatsoever.
这给了他们难以置信的繁殖能力
That gives them an incredible ability to regenerate.
谢帕德少校看到的移动是怎么回事？
What about the movement Major Sheppard saw?
就那种行为而言
As far as independent behavior,
我认为他看到的移动，是由他们被切断的
神经末梢上多余的命令语言造成的
I say that anything he saw was caused by a residual command language
in the severed nerve endings.
好吧，还有呢？
All right, anything else?
我敢打赌
The being this arm belonged to,
拥有这只胳膊的生物
if I was a betting man,
他们的历史很悠久
I’d say it was old.
非常非常悠久
Very, very old.
多久？
How old?
只要这些细胞能获得合适的养分
As long as the cells are properly nourished,
这种生物不会像地球人那样，
因为年龄增长而自然死亡
I don’t see a life form like this ever
dying of natural aging the way we do.
而且要杀死他们很困难
And they’d be bloody hard to kill.
真是个坏消息
Well I don’t like the sound of that.
我不想诅咒
I don’t blame ya.
什么声音？ 我，我不知道
- What is that noise?
- I... I don’t…
刚刚他还在这儿
he was right here.
少校？
Major!
你说过你想拥有战术优势
You said you wanted tactical advantage.
是的
All right,
你能驾驶那玩意儿
so you can fly that thing.
这并不意味着你能拯救他们
It doesn’t mean you can pull off a rescue.
博士，这是你把我带到这来的意义
Doctor, this is why you brought me here.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
我不知道
I have no idea.
这些技术比我们先进太多了
This technology is so far beyond us.
我不知道该怎么操作，我只能...
We don’t have a clue what we’re dealing
with. For all I know we could…
是的，我准备好了
Yeah, I’m ready.
好了，朋友，准备出发
All right boys, get ready to go.
星门飞船一号，出发吧！
Gate Ship One, ready to go.
星门飞船一号？
Gate Ship One?
就像这样的小汽艇吗？
A little puddle jumper like this?
这是会穿越星门的飞船
It’s a ship, it goes through the gate.
星门飞船一号 哦，不，不，这名字不好
- Gate Ship One.
- Oh no, no, no. That’s all wrong.
迈凯博士认为这名字很酷 哦，好吧，这算官方名字
- Dr. McKay thought it was cool.
- Oh, okay. Well it’s official.
你是不是没起过名字？从来没有？
You don’t get to name anything… ever.
基地，这里是小汽艇 我们要起飞了
Flight, this is Puddle Jumper;
we’re go to launch.
好吧，这里是基地，
我以为我们会用星门飞船这个名字？
All right, this is Flight.
I thought we were going with Gate Ship?
不行，基地
Negative, Flight.
请待命
Stand by.
这是一个穿越星门的飞船，我...
It’s a ship that goes through the gate. I…
好的
Fine.
小汽艇，你们可以起飞了
Puddle Jumper you are clear for launch.
中尉，拨号吧
Dial it up, Lieutenant.
祝你们一路平安
Be safe.
哇，很酷哦
Wow. This is cool.
看来好像你已经掌握它的窍门了
Looks like you got the hang of it.
告诉你吧，中尉
I’ll tell you what Lieutenant
很多飞行员做梦都想驾驶这玩意
a lot of fighter pilots would kill to fly this thing.
好像它能看穿你的想法
It’s like it reads your mind.
这是你办到的？
Did you do that?
我正在想我们要去哪
I was just wondering where we go from here.
那我就当是你做到的罗
I’ll take that as a ‘yes’.
我们着陆后怎么去找他们？
So how do we find them once we land?
我也正在想这个问题
Well I’ve been thinking about that too.
我正在想一块美味的火鸡三明治
Now I’m thinking about a nice turkey sandwich.
值得尝尝
Worth a try.
锁定，装弹
Lock and load.
现在，第二队
All right, teams of two.
尽你们所能建好防线
Learn what you can;
lay down the defenses as you see fit.
如果需要的话 我会炸掉这个地方
I wanna be able to light this place up if we have to.
两响后允许交谈 遵命，长官
- Two clicks and you’re clear to talk.
- Yes sir.
不要与敌人交战
Do not engage the enemy.
你跟我来
You’re with me.
你现在一定感到饿了吧？
You must feel hunger by now.
我还以为进来是是最难的一关呢
I thought getting in was gonna be the hard part.
这是我们看到的第一个人
That’s the first one we’ve seen.
这个移动的小点应该就是他
The moving dot should be him.
去那里
Over there.
没错，这是你
Yeah, that’s you.
就是说，我们有一个生命显示仪了？
So, we got ourselves a Life Signs Detector.
以后再给他命名吧
You can name it later.
少校
- Major.
嘘
- Shh.
你们还好吗？
- Are you all right?
你怎么找到我们的？
- How did you find us?
我儿子还活着吗？ 他很好，正在等你呢
- Is my son alive?
- He’s well and waiting for you.
萨姆勒上校在哪儿？ 幻影族把他带走了
- Where’s Colonel Sumner?
- He was taken by the Wraith.
我们不知道去哪儿了
We don’t know where.
那什么时候呢？
- How about when?
不久
- Not long.
我知道有些不对劲
I knew something had to go wrong.
这是斯塔克豪斯，请说，长官
This is Stackhouse, go ahead Sir.
来个诱敌行动怎么样？
How ‘bout a diversion a little bit?
我们需要你在外面制造些动静 遵命，长官
- We’re gonna need to make some noise out there.
- Yes, Sir.
埋一个C4 塑胶炸弹，炸个洞出来
Rig up the C4 to blow a hole
等我发出暗号，你就带他们逃出来
and get these people out of here
on my signal, all right?
我可以用这个东西找到上校，
这附近没有那么多的幻影族人
I can find the Colonel with this,
there aren’t that many Wraith around.
我应该能办到的
I should be able to do this.
如果我二十分钟之内还没回来 把这洞炸掉，然后逃出去
If I’m not back in 20 minutes,
blow the cells and get out.
你是唯一能带他们飞出去的人了
You’re the only one who
can fly these people out of here.
我会带所有人都飞出去，包括上校在内
Yeah I’m gonna fly us all out of here,
including the Colonel.
我是说我应该去救上校
I’m saying I should be the one to go, Sir.
二十分钟，我会找到他的
Twenty minutes, I’ll find him.
你叫什么？
What do you call yourself?
马歇尔·萨姆勒上校
Colonel Marshall Sumner,
美国海军陆战队
United States Marine Corps.
你不太害怕？是因为勇气还是无知？
So little fear. Is it valor or ignorance?
我们穿越星门进行和平的宇宙探险
We traveled through the stargate
as peaceful explorers.
你必须吃东西
You must eat,
但是你抵抗了饥饿，为什么？
yet you resist your hunger. Why?
你为什么把我们的人关到监狱里？
Why have you taken my people prisoner?
你们闯入了我们的食品场
You trespassed upon our feeding ground
食品场？
Feeding ground?
所有的生物都必须吃东西
All living things must eat.
我相信在这一点上我们是一样的
In this I am sure we are similar.
你现在已经饿了
You feel hunger even now,
我能感觉到
I can sense it.
但是，你在抵抗你的饥饿感
Yet, you resist.
为什么？
Why?
你为什么关心这个？
Why do you care?
饥饿
Hunger…
是很不好受的
is distasteful.
我感觉“食物”们好像不同意
Looks to me like the food didn’t agree with him.
萨姆勒上校，这一点我们很不同
There we are quite dissimilar,
Colonel Sumner.
我不需要让食物同意我们的看法
We don’t require our food to agree with us.
你们的星球叫什么名字？
What do you call your world?
地球
Earth.
不在我们的星系里吧？
It is not among our stars.
不在
No.
给我讲讲地球
Tell me of earth.
像你这样的在地球上有多少？
How many more are there of your kind.
几千？
Thousands?
几百万？还是更多？
Millions? More?
一万年以来，我们的食品
从来没有如此丰富过
Our feeding ground has not been
so rich in ten thousand years.
你的意志很强大
Your will is strong.
这个尸体渴望新生
This one begged for his life.
这就是你们打算对我和我的人民做的吗？
Is that the kind of treatment I
can expect for myself and my people?
正如我所说的，所有的生物都必须吃东西
As I have said, all living things must eat.
那就没什么好谈的了
Then we’re done talking.
我认为不是
I think not.
跪下
Kneel.
我好久没有碰到过如此强大的意志了
I have not tasted such strength in so long.
去死吧
Go to hell.
第一个地球人
Earth first.
我要减少你多少年的寿命，
你才能告诉我想所知道的东西？
How many years must I take from you before you tell us what I wish to know?
还是要我把它们全部夺走？
Or shall I take them all?
这个新的食品场在哪里？
Where is this new feeding ground?
我不会告诉你的
I won’t-
把他带过来
Bring him.
你的手感觉如何？
How’s the hand feeling?
好多了
Much better.
听你这么说我真失望
I’m sorry to hear that.
你怎么会有这个东西？
How did this come to you?
我忘了
I don’t remember.
引爆
Light it up.
隐蔽
Cover.
这样应该能杀死你
That has to kill you.
你怎么找到我的
How’d you find me?
顺着你的脚印，我们快走吧，长官
Tread marks, standard issue. Sir, let’s go.
你不知道你们这样做的后果
You don’t know what you have done.
我们是这些睡着的同类的保护者
We are merely the caretakers for those that sleep.
当我死了，其它人就会醒
When I die the others will waken.
所有的都会醒
All of them.
她在说什么？
What’s she talking about?
还有多少敌人？
How many are left?
长官，我们得赶快走
Sir, we need to leave.
贝慈，我们撤了
Bates, we’re on the go.
- 我们就在这，萨姆勒上校呢？
- 没有救出来
- So are we. Colonel Sumner?
- Negative.
韦尔博士
Dr. Weir!
我们接到了来自整个城市的报告
We’re getting reports in from all over the city.
一些，很有趣的东西
Some… uh… pretty interesting stuff.
我们只能给部分地区供应能量
We’ve only been able to provide
power to certain sections,
但是即使那样，即将发生的…
but even then,
the things that are coming up are just-
我不应该让他们去
I should never have let them go.
因为不值得？
For what it’s worth,
你的决策是正确的
you made the right decision.
给他们时间
Give them time.
少校
Major,
现在汽艇很安全
the Jumper is secure for the moment,
但我们有大麻烦了
- but we have a big problem.
中尉，带这六个人走
- Lieutenant, take our six.
我把他们带到汽艇上去
I’m gonna take them back to the Jumper.
我就跟在你后面
Be right behind you.
那什么都没有
There’s nothing there.
我确定我看见什么了
I was sure I saw something.
只有幻影族想让你看到的东西
Only what the Wraith wish you to see.
开火会暴露我们的位置
Firing your weapon will reveal our position.
走吧
Come on.
快进去！
Get in!
谢谢你，长官
Thank you, Sir.
不要总这样好吗？
Let’s try not to make a habit of this.
我们赶快进去！
We have incoming!
天啊，现在我该想什么？
Okay, now what am I thinking?
你们都还好吗？
Everybody okay back there?
我们很好
We are well enough.
希望刚才那是最困难的部分
Hope that was the hard part.
该死！
Crap.
我觉得我们还没到最困难的一关
I don’t think we’ve gotten to the hard part yet.
我们怎么办？
What can we do?
只要他们看不见我们，我们就安全了
We’re safe as long as they can’t see us.
他们不用看见我们，
我们只有一条道可走
They don't have to.
There’s only one way for us to go.
只要我们一启动星门，
他们就会盲目射击
The minute we activate the stargate
they could start shooting blind
我们一靠近星门，
他们就会把我们射下来
and blow us away on our approach.
那我们怎么穿越星门？
Then how can we get through?
我们必须把他们引开，然后再返回来
We have to draw them away
from the gate and double back.
我一下命令，你们就准备拨号
Be prepared to dial the gate on my mark.
你看见那有个
好像武器操纵台的东西吗？
You see anything like a weapons console over there?
试着再次隐身
Try and go invisible again.
我试了，但好像坏了，启动星门
I tried, it must be damaged.
Dial the gate.
星际之门打开！
Gate activation!
打开防御系统！
Raise the shield.
在下一次经过时准备按下身份码
Be ready to punch in your code on the next pass.
这个东西覆盖的距离有多远？
What’s the range on these things?
收到身份验证码了吗？
Do we have an identification code?
还没有
Nothing yet.
输入验证码
Enter your code.
坚持住
Hang on.
我收到了福特中尉的身份验证码
I’m reading Lt. Ford’s IDC.
让他进来
Let him in.
再多等几秒钟
Give them a few more seconds.
我们开的太快了
We’re going too fast.
我知道
I know.
再次启动防御系统！
Reactivate the shield!
女士们先生们
Ladies and Gentlemen,
欢迎来到亚特兰蒂斯
Welcome to Atlantis.
请一直坐在这里
Please remain seated
直到小汽艇完全停下来
until the Puddle Jumper
has come to a full complete stop.
我猜这就是家了
- I guess this is home now.
大概是吧
- Guess so.
我在想一个有海景的小地方
I’m thinking of a little place with an ocean view.
很不一般
Out of the way.
少校
Major,
中尉
Lieutenant,
我认为现在这个时候最值得打开它
I thought the occasion merited opening this.
奥尼尔将军的奖赏
Compliments of General O’Neill.
干杯
Cheers.
你做得很棒，约翰
You did good, John.
我不这么认为
I don’t know about that.
嗨，你没有办法拯救萨姆勒上校
Hey, there was no way you
could have saved Colonel Sumner.
我必须承受这个结果
I have to live with it.
我开始觉得你是正确的，
我让事情变得更糟
I’m beginning to think you were right,
I have made things much worse.
我没有让大家交更多的朋友
I haven’t made us many more friends out there.
没有吗？
No?
看看你周围
Look around you.
谢帕德少校，她说的对
I agree, Major Sheppard.
你已经赢得了我的友谊
You have earned both
my friendship
还有我族人的
and that of my people.
在我们的帮助下，
你们可以交更多的朋友
With our help you will make many more friends.
我怎么不能像他那样交朋友？
How come I never make friends like that?
你需要多多外出
You need to get out more.
但我们在另一个星球上，
你能多出去多少次呢？
We’re in another galaxy.
How much more out can you get?
这东西里有柠檬吗？
Is there lemon in this?
还有一件事情，少校
One more thing Major.
有些问题需要你考虑一下
It’s something I’d like you to sleep on.
我已经想过了，但是......
- I have a few thoughts for it myself, but-
想过什么？
- Thoughts for what?
谁会是你队伍中的成员？
Who the members of your team might be?
我的队伍？
My team?
现在你已经是有头衔的军官了
Well you are the ranking military officer now,
或者你需要我提醒一下那件事？
or do you need to be reminded of that?
我们需要从这里回去
We need to get back out there;
好好去做我们该做的事情
do what we came to do.
你确实意识到我能把大家带进各种... 麻烦 对吗？
You do realize I could get us into all sorts of
… trouble. Ya ready?